♪The autumn wind slips in, never asking when I'll return♪
♪نسيم الخريف يتسلل، دون أن يسأل متى سأعود♪
♪Before the mirror, I comb my hair, lips parted just so♪
♪أمام المرآة، أمشط شعري، شفتاي مفتوحتان بهدوء♪
♪An old melody plays faintly, perhaps the answer to this life♪
♪لحن قديم يعزف بخفة، ربما هو جواب هذه الحياة♪
♪If fate leaves any trace at all♪
♪إذا كان القدر يترك أي أثر♪
♪Wild geese disappear in the woods, flowers wither at dusk♪
♪الإوز البري يختفي في الغابة، الزهور تذبل عند الغسق♪
♪How cruel the moonlight flooding the empty tower, wine growing cold♪
♪كم هو قاسٍ ضوء القمر الذي يغمر البرج الفارغ، والنبيذ يبرد♪
♪Long dreams and night rain tearing through the heart of Luoyang♪
♪أحلام طويلة ومطر الليل يمزق قلب لويانغ♪
♪Who still rides forth to keep a vow long left behind?♪
♪من لا يزال يركض ليحفظ وعدًا طويلاً ترك وراءه؟♪
♪Paint the love and the hate♪
♪ارسم الحب والكراهية♪
♪With gentle strokes of ink, like a lone wild goose flying far away♪
♪بضربات حبر لطيفة، مثل إوزة برية وحيدة تطير بعيدًا♪
♪Frost and snow to sketch memories, drawn taut like a bow♪
♪الصقيع والثلج لرسم الذكريات، مشدودة مثل القوس♪
♪One arrow dyed in deepest red♪
♪سهم واحد ملون بأحمر عميق♪
♪The bitter chill within my heart♪
♪البرد المر في قلبي♪
♪The sorrow falling between your brows♪
♪الحزن الذي يسقط بين حاجبيك♪
♪Scalding memories lodged in my throat♪
♪ذكريات حارقة عالقة في حلقي♪
♪Burning away the warmth we once shared♪
♪تحرق الدفء الذي كنا نتشاركه ذات يوم♪
♪I would fade away with the candle's shadow♪
♪سأتلاشى مع ظل الشمعة♪
♪Sever the ties and stay behind alone♪
♪اقطع الروابط وابقَ وحيدًا♪
♪Let you go♪
♪دعك تذهب♪
♪Your sorrow lingers as you glance back♪
♪حزنك يبقى بينما تلقي نظرة للخلف♪
♪This longing has already worn me thin♪
♪هذا الشوق قد أضعفني بالفعل♪
♪We once vowed to grow old together♪
♪كنا ذات يوم نعد بأن نشيخ معًا♪
♪But if fate bears no guilt, then why♪
♪ولكن إذا كان القدر لا يحمل ذنبًا، فلماذا♪
♪Does it play this song of tears for me alone?♪
♪يعزف هذه الأغنية من الدموع لي وحدي؟♪
=Destiny of Love= (Adapted from Lin Nan's novel, Destiny of Love.)
=قدر الحب= (مقتبس من رواية لين نان، قدر الحب.)
=Episode 16=
=الحلقة 16=
Your Highness, you have a fever.
سموك، لديك حمى.
I'll prepare the medicine.
سأحضر الدواء.
That's true.
هذا صحيح.
I need to get better soon.
أحتاج أن أتحسن قريبًا.
How can I let her
كيف يمكنني أن أدعها
see me like this?
تراني هكذا؟
Why hasn't she come yet?
لماذا لم تأتِ بعد؟
Little Cloud.
سحابة صغيرة.
It's pouring. Why didn't you take cover?
السماء تمطر. لماذا لم تتحصن؟
I was afraid you wouldn't see me.
كنت خائفًا من ألا تراني.
Did they hit you again?
هل ضربوك مرة أخرى؟
But it's okay.
لكن لا بأس.
I have you.
لديّك.
Of course, you have me.
بالطبع، لديكِني.
You're the little brother I protect.
أنت الأخ الصغير الذي أحميه.
Will you always stay with me and never leave me behind?
هل ستبقى معي دائمًا ولن تتركني أبدًا؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
I'll watch over my Little Cloud
سأراقب سحابتي الصغيرة
until he grows into a Big Cloud.
حتى يكبر ويصبح سحابة كبيرة.
Don't forget to come tomorrow.
لا تنسى أن تأتي غدًا.
I got you a gift.
لقد أحضرت لك هدية.
Yes.
نعم.
Why hasn't she come yet?
لماذا لم تأتِ بعد؟
♪Fate ties us in endless threads♪
♪القدر يربطنا بخيوط لا تنتهي♪
♪We share the same moonlight♪
♪نشارك نفس ضوء القمر♪
♪The vow of this life never changed♪
♪عهد هذه الحياة لم يتغير أبدًا♪
♪One glance, and I was bound for ages♪
♪نظرة واحدة، وكنت مقيدًا لقرون♪
♪You are the moon above the mountain♪ I've been busy packing lately.
♪أنت القمر فوق الجبل♪ كنت مشغولًا بالتعبئة مؤخرًا.
♪So radiant you keep me sleepless♪ Mr. Ji is taking me away.
♪مشرق جدًا لدرجة أنك تبقيني مستيقظًا♪ السيد جي يأخذني بعيدًا.
♪Radiance hidden in a sea of clouds♪ The bunny ears will be here with you.
♪إشراق مخفي في بحر من الغيوم♪ أذنا الأرنب ستكون هنا معك.
♪Fading and returning♪
♪يتلاشى ويعود♪
♪Fireflies flicker at the foot of the hills♪
♪اليراعات تومض عند سفح التلال♪
♪Swaying, drifting into the distance♪
♪تتمايل، تنجرف إلى البعيد♪
♪With a reed to sail, I wear your light in my dreams♪
♪مع قصبة للإبحار، أرتدي نورك في أحلامي♪
I'll be right here waiting for you.
سأكون هنا في انتظارك.
His Majesty's birthday is a joyous occasion.
عيد ميلاد جلالته مناسبة سعيدة.
They added a special imperial exam this year.
أضافوا امتحانًا إمبراطوريًا خاصًا هذا العام.
No need to wait another three years!
لا حاجة للانتظار ثلاث سنوات أخرى!
Make way.
أفسحوا الطريق.
Starting today, you can take the imperial exam.
بدءًا من اليوم، يمكنك تقديم الامتحان الإمبراطوري.
What wonderful news!
يا لها من أخبار رائعة!
(Special Exam on His Majesty's Birthday) Finally, we can sit for one this year!
(امتحان خاص في عيد ميلاد جلالته) أخيرًا، يمكننا تقديمه هذا العام!
(No more waiting!)
(لا مزيد من الانتظار!)
(The exam begins today!) That's right.
(الامتحان يبدأ اليوم!) هذا صحيح.
If I pass the exam...
إذا نجحت في الامتحان...
A bright future is just around the corner!
مستقبل مشرق على الأبواب!
It's a blessing, indeed.
إنها نعمة بالفعل.
Truly a blessing.
نعمة حقيقية.
Dad, where is Fang?
أبي، أين فانغ؟
Didn't Madam Zhang come by just now?
ألم تأتِ السيدة تشانغ للتو؟
She said pork was cheap today.
قالت إن لحم الخنزير كان رخيصًا اليوم.
Fang went out with her to buy some.
فانغ خرجت معها لشراء بعضه.
Dad...
أبي...
She's a Princess of Xilin.
إنها أميرة من زيلين.
Yet she's living a humble life with me.
مع ذلك، تعيش حياة متواضعة معي.
It pains me to see this.
يؤلمني رؤية هذا.
She is a princess without her memory.
إنها أميرة بدون ذاكرتها.
For now, she can only be a commoner.
في الوقت الحالي، يمكنها فقط أن تكون شخصًا عاديًا.
No!
لا!
No? What do you plan to do?
لا؟ ماذا تخطط أن تفعل؟
You're just a teacher.
أنت مجرد معلم.
I'm old.
أنا كبير في السن.
Can the two of us
هل يمكننا نحن الاثنان
turn Everything Guild into a royal palace?
تحويل نقابة "إيفريثينغ" إلى قصر ملكي؟
If not a palace, then at least a proper manor.
إذا لم يكن قصرًا، فعلى الأقل منزلًا لائقًا.
You must be dreaming, boy!
لا بد أنك تحلم، يا فتى!
Dad, stop fussing.
أبي، توقف عن القلق.
Just hear me out.
فقط استمع إلي.
Alright, speak.
حسنًا، تكلم.
Today...
اليوم...
I heard they added an exam for His Majesty's birthday.
سمعت أنهم أضافوا امتحانًا بمناسبة عيد ميلاد جلالته.
I'd been hesitating whether or not
كنت أتردد في ما إذا
I should sit for it.
يجب أن أجلس له.
But, I've made up my mind.
لكنني قررت.
I'll take the exam and I will pass.
سأخوض الامتحان وسأجتازه.
Only then can I give her a good life
فقط عندها يمكنني أن أعطيها حياة جيدة
and be worthy of her.
وأكون جديرًا بها.
Son...
يا بني...
The imperial exam is a good thing.
الامتحان الإمبراطوري شيء جيد.
You have my full support.
لديك دعمي الكامل.
But,
لكن،
the exam isn't easy.
الامتحان ليس سهلًا.
Scholars flood the capital
يغمر العلماء العاصمة
like an overflowing river.
مثل نهر يفيض.
To stand out among them,
لتبرز بينهم،
that's no small feat.
هذا ليس إنجازًا بسيطًا.
It's a steep climb.
إنه صعود شديد الانحدار.
Dad. Dear.
أبي. عزيزي.
I bought pork.
اشتريت لحم الخنزير.
We can have a good meal tonight!
يمكننا أن نتناول وجبة جيدة الليلة!
Wonderful!
رائع!
Hold on.
انتظر.
One day, I'll make sure you eat well every day,
يومًا ما، سأحرص على أن تأكلوا جيدًا كل يوم،
with abalone, shark fin, and fish maw!
مع الأبالون، زعانف القرش، وحويصلة السمك!
Abalone, shark fin, and fish maw?
الأبالون، زعانف القرش، وحويصلة السمك؟
Dad.
أبي.
What's gotten into him?
ماذا حدث له؟
He's lost his mind.
لقد فقد عقله.
Abalone and all...
الأبالون وكل ذلك...
What nonsense is that?
ما هذا الهراء؟
(I look forward to our meeting.)
(أتطلع إلى لقائنا.)
Deliver this invitation to Manman in person.
سلم هذه الدعوة إلى مانمان شخصيًا.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Why are you standing there? Go, now!
لماذا تقف هناك؟ اذهب الآن!
Yes.
نعم.
(Benevolent and Kind)
(رحيم وطيب)
To My Princess Consort,
إلى زوجتي الأميرة،
the skies have cleared and are washed.
السماء قد صفت واغتسلت.
Alas, spring fades too swiftly,
للأسف، الربيع يزول بسرعة كبيرة،
and too lovely to bear alone.
وجميل جدًا لتحمله وحدي.
Thus, I humbly extend this invitation.
لذلك، أقدم هذه الدعوة بتواضع.
Do grace me with your presence.
تفضلي بتشريفنا بحضورك.
You will be received with utmost sincerity.
سيتم استقبالك بأقصى درجات الإخلاص.
From Jin.
من جين.
Well? Does it sound sincere enough?
حسنًا؟ هل تبدو صادقة بما يكفي؟
Not bad.
ليس سيئًا.
Better than the others.
أفضل من الآخرين.
And heartfelt too.
ومليئة بالمشاعر أيضًا.
But...
لكن...
Isn't the wording a bit over the top?
أليست الصيغة مبالغ فيها قليلاً؟
Then, what should I just write,
إذن، ماذا يجب أن أكتب،
"Nice weather today."
"الجو جميل اليوم."
"I really want to see you."
"أريد حقًا أن أراك."
"Please come?"
"هل تأتين؟"
That's perfect! I like it!
هذا مثالي! يعجبني!
The best so far.
الأفضل حتى الآن.
Just write it like that.
فقط اكتبها هكذا.
Trust me.
ثق بي.
Trust you, my foot.
أثق بك؟ مستحيل.
Get up already.
انهض بالفعل.
Deliver this invitation to Princess Consort.
سلم هذه الدعوة إلى زوجة الأمير.
Yes!
نعم!
"The skies have cleared
"السماء قد صفت
and are washed..."
واغتسلت..."
"Spring fades..."
"الربيع يزول..."
What's this?
ما هذا؟
"Your presence..."
"حضورك..."
What is all this?
ما كل هذا؟
What Jiufeng means is,
ما يعنيه جيوفنغ هو،
His Highness said,
قال سموه،
"The weather's great today.
"الجو رائع اليوم.
He really wants to see you.
هو حقًا يريد أن يراك.
Please come."
تفضلي بالحضور."
Why not just say that?
لماذا لا يقول ذلك فقط؟
Why write all this sappy nonsense?
لماذا يكتب كل هذا الكلام العاطفي؟
Well, doesn't it show sincerity?
حسنًا، ألا يظهر ذلك الإخلاص؟
So? Will you go?
إذن؟ هل ستذهبين؟
Your Highness.
سموك.
Guihu sent an invitation
غويهو أرسل دعوة
from Prince Yunnuo.
من الأمير يوننو.
He said it must be read by you personally.
قال أنه يجب أن تقرئيه بنفسك.
Guihu is waiting outside for your reply.
غويهو ينتظر خارجًا ردك.
Prince Yunnuo?
الأمير يوننو؟
Tell Guihu
أخبر غويهو
I have matters to attend to today and can't meet him.
لدي أمور لأهتم بها اليوم ولا أستطيع مقابلته.
Send my apologies.
أرسل اعتذاري.
Yes.
نعم.
Matters to attend to?
أمور لتُهتم بها؟
Are you seeing His Highness?
هل ستقابلين سموه؟
Well...
حسنًا...
His Highness put a lot of thought into writing the invitation.
سموه بذل جهدًا كبيرًا في كتابة الدعوة.
I'd feel bad if I turned him down.
سأشعر بالسوء إذا رفضته.
Well?
إذن؟
She...
هي...
Spill it.
قلها.
She says
تقول
she has other matters to tend to. She can't meet you today.
لديها أمور أخرى لتهتم بها. لا تستطيع مقابلتك اليوم.
What matters is she tending to?
ما هي الأمور التي تهتم بها؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
When I was waiting outside for her reply,
عندما كنت أنتظر خارجًا ردها،
a carriage was readied.
تم تجهيز عربة.
I asked those servants.
سألت الخدم.
They say
قالوا
Prince Jin is heading out.
الأمير جين سيخرج.
Perhaps Princess Consort Jin is going with him too.
ربما ستذهب الأميرة القرينة جين معه أيضًا.
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did she choose him, not me?
لماذا اختارته وليس أنا؟
Why is everyone so kind to him?
لماذا الجميع لطيفون معه؟
Why does Fu Chengjin always outshine me?
لماذا دائمًا ما يتفوق عليّ فو تشينغجين؟
Your Highness, you're still unwell.
سموك، ما زلت مريضًا.
Please don't upset yourself.
من فضلك لا تغضب نفسك.
Your Highness!
سموك!
Go tell her...
اذهب وأخبرها...
I was ambushed by an assassin and was wounded.
لقد تعرضت لكمين من قبل قاتل وأصبت.
Beg her to come see me.
توسل إليها أن تأتي لتراني.
Your Highness, your health is more important.
سموك، صحتك أهم.
Go!
اذهب!
Guihu.
غويهو.
Why are you still standing there?
لماذا ما زلت واقفًا هناك؟
Go!
اذهب!
Yes.
نعم.
Your Highness.
سموك.
Prince Yunnuo was attacked
تعرض الأمير يونوهو للهجوم
and gravely injured.
وأصيب إصابة بالغة.
He begs you to visit.
إنه يتوسل إليك لزيارته.
Assassins?
قتلة؟
Where was he wounded?
أين أصيب؟
It's urgent.
الأمر عاجل.
You'll know once you see him.
ستعرف بمجرد رؤيته.
Prince Yunnuo is too attached to me.
الأمير يونوهو مرتبط بي كثيرًا.
Guihu, you're loyal to him.
غويهو، أنت مخلص له.
You understand well enough.
أنت تفهم جيدًا.
Must I say more?
هل يجب أن أقول المزيد؟
I won't see him again.
لن أراه مرة أخرى.
Please, Your Highness, go see him.
من فضلك، سموك، اذهب لرؤيته.
You two are both stubborn as mules.
أنتما عنيدان مثل البغال.
(Forgive me, Little Cloud...)
(اغفر لي، يا سحابة صغيرة...)
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
Your Highness...
سموك...
I've failed you.
لقد خذلتك.
I couldn't bring her here.
لم أستطع إحضارها إلى هنا.
Why didn't she come?
لماذا لم تأتي؟
Speak!
تكلم!
She says
قالت
you should summon a physician.
يجب أن تستدعي طبيبًا.
What else?
ماذا أيضًا؟
She also says
قالت أيضًا
there's no need to meet if your paths differ.
لا داعي للقاء إذا كانت طرقكما مختلفة.
She won't come.
لن تأتي.
No. This can't be allowed to happen.
لا. لا يمكن السماح بحدوث هذا.
I get it now.
لقد فهمت الآن.
I haven't done enough.
لم أفعل ما يكفي.
If I invite her every day,
إذا دعوتها كل يوم،
she will surely understand.
ستفهم بالتأكيد.
Your Highness!
سموك!
She doesn't care for you.
إنها لا تهتم بك.
She left right after to meet Prince Jin.
غادرت على الفور للقاء الأمير جين.
Enough!
يكفي!
Why...
لماذا...
Why?
لماذا؟
I found her first!
لقد وجدتها أولاً!
Get out!
اخرج!
Leave!
اغرب!
I was the one who found you first...
كنت أنا من وجدك أولاً...
It was me! I found you first!
كنت أنا! أنا من وجدك أولاً!
Why?
لماذا؟
I need to make two little ears...
أحتاج إلى صنع أذنين صغيرتين...
Two little ears...
أذنين صغيرتين...
How do I wrap it?
كيف ألتفها؟
Why won't it stay in place?
لماذا لا تبقى في مكانها؟
Your Highness.
سموك.
Why did you bring me here?
لماذا أحضرتني إلى هنا؟
Jiufeng.
جيوفينغ.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Your Highness, where are you taking me?
سموك، إلى أين تأخذني؟
Your Highness?
سموك؟
What are you up to?
ماذا تفعل؟
Your Highness.
سموك.
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Do you know what day it is?
هل تعلمين أي يوم هو اليوم؟
Have you forgotten?
هل نسيتِ؟
Didn't you say
ألم تقولي
you wanted to watch fireworks
أنكِ تريدين مشاهدة الألعاب النارية
with someone dear on your birthday?
مع شخص عزيز في عيد ميلادكِ؟
This is my surprise for you.
هذه هي مفاجأتي لكِ.
Do you like it?
هل أعجبكِ؟
I do.
نعم.
If you like fireworks,
إذا كنتِ تحبين الألعاب النارية،
I'll light up the entire sky for you.
سأضيء السماء بأكملها من أجلكِ.
If you like firefly lamps,
إذا كنتِ تحبين مصابيح اليراعات،
I'll light the whole street for you.
سأضيء الشارع بأكمله من أجلكِ.
If you love the trees and grass of this world,
إذا كنتِ تحبين الأشجار والعشب في هذا العالم،
then I too will cherish every bit of it.
فسأعتز بكل جزء منه أيضًا.
Before I met you,
قبل أن ألتقي بكِ،
every step I took was to get away from this palace.
كانت كل خطوة أخطوها للابتعاد عن هذا القصر.
But after meeting you,
ولكن بعد أن التقيت بكِ،
every step I took...
كانت كل خطوة أخطوها...
was just to be a little closer to you.
فقط لأكون أقرب إليكِ قليلاً.
But...
لكن...
But I was never part of your plan.
لكنني لم أكن أبدًا جزءًا من خطتكِ.
You were never an accident to me.
لم تكوني أبدًا حادثًا بالنسبة لي.
You are the surprise in my long life.
أنتِ المفاجأة في حياتي الطويلة.
The one I wish to spend the rest of my life with.
الشخص الذي أتمنى قضاء بقية حياتي معه.
But I've been lying to you all along.
لكنني كنت أكذب عليكِ طوال الوقت.
I was never Princess Aliya.
لم أكن أبدًا الأميرة علياء.
I've known that for a long time.
كنت أعلم ذلك منذ وقت طويل.
But more importantly,
ولكن الأهم من ذلك،
it was you who lit the firefly lamps for me.
أنتِ من أضاء مصابيح اليراعات من أجلي.
You learned medicine for me.
تعلمت الطب من أجلي.
You peeled lotus seeds for me.
قشرت بذور اللوتس من أجلي.
And you were willing to leave the palace for me.
وكنت مستعدًا لمغادرة القصر من أجلي.
Princess Aliya
الأميرة علياء
was never my Princess Consort Jin.
لم تكن أبدًا زوجتي الأميرة جين.
The one who came to me in that palanquin
الشخص الذي جاء إليّ في تلك الهودج
is my Princess Consort Jin.
هو زوجتي الأميرة جين.
It took me so long to find you.
استغرق مني وقتًا طويلاً للعثور عليكِ.
Please don't leave me again.
من فضلكِ لا تتركيني مرة أخرى.
♪If everything could overcome all barriers and fall in love♪
♪إذا كان كل شيء يمكنه التغلب على كل الحواجز والوقوع في الحب♪
♪Even the cloud and sea could be together♪
♪حتى السحابة والبحر يمكن أن يكونا معًا♪
♪Forget how far from shore and how dangerous it is♪
♪انسَ مدى البعد عن الشاطئ ومدى خطورته♪
♪We can't see♪
♪لا يمكننا الرؤية♪
♪If distance can't tear us apart and it's not hard to endure♪
♪إذا كانت المسافة لا يمكنها أن تفرقنا وليس من الصعب تحملها♪
♪Our tears will stay together♪
♪ستبقى دموعنا معًا♪
♪Don't forget the love♪
♪لا تنسَ الحب♪
♪They could♪
♪يمكنهم♪
♪Never have♪
♪لم يفعلوا أبدًا♪
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب ورحيم)
Why have all my things been moved to your room?
لماذا تم نقل كل أشيائي إلى غرفتك؟
I had Jiufeng move them.
طلبت من جيوفينغ نقلها.
That was rather fast.
كان ذلك سريعًا إلى حد ما.
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
I said the wind outside was quite strong.
قلت إن الرياح الخارجية كانت قوية جدًا.
It is.
إنها كذلك.
It's making me a little dizzy.
إنها تجعلني أشعر بالدوار قليلاً.
If you're feeling dizzy,
إذا كنت تشعر بالدوار،
perhaps we should sleep early.
ربما ينبغي أن ننام مبكرًا.
I'll stay and watch you sleep.
سأبقى وأراقبك وأنت نائم.
Manman...
مانمان...
(She actually fell asleep...)
(لقد نامت بالفعل...)
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب ورحيم)
Your Highness?
صاحب السمو؟
(Matters at court.)
(أمور في البلاط.)
(Remember to eat breakfast.)
(تذكر أن تتناول الإفطار.)
This is my pet.
هذا حيواني الأليف.
Take care of it.
اعتنِ به.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll take great care of it.
سأعتني به جيدًا.
Manman, you're back!
مامان، لقد عدتِ!
Counting your coins?
هل تعدين نقودك؟
Don't just stand there.
لا تقفي هناك فقط.
Go wash up inside.
اذهبي لتغتسلي في الداخل.
The meal is almost ready.
الوجبة على وشك أن تكون جاهزة.
Mr. Ji...
السيد جي...
There's something I want to tell you.
هناك شيء أريد أن أخبرك به.
Go on.
تابع.
It's about...
إنه عن...
Spit it out already.
قلها بالفعل.
As long as you didn't expose yourself to Prince Jin,
طالما أنك لم تكشف نفسك للأمير جين،
it's all good.
فكل شيء على ما يرام.
Mr. Ji...
السيد جي...
You really are amazing.
أنت حقًا مذهل.
Of course I am.
بالطبع أنا كذلك.
I am never wrong!
أنا لا أخطئ أبدًا!
So what you're saying is...
إذن ما تقوله هو...
If your...
إذا كان...
If your true identity is exposed,
إذا تم الكشف عن هويتك الحقيقية،
you will be charged with treason.
سيتم اتهامك بالخيانة.
But I never meant to deceive anyone.
لكنني لم أقصد خداع أحد.
Seriously, what were you thinking?
بجدية، ماذا كنت تفكر؟
Even if not for yourself,
حتى لو لم يكن من أجل نفسك،
at least think about Ji Mo! You...
على الأقل فكر في جي مو! أنت...
Ji Mo's about to take the imperial exam.
جي مو على وشك تقديم الامتحان الإمبراطوري.
And me?
وأنا؟
I'm getting old.
أنا أصبحت كبيرًا في السن.
I haven't held a grandchild yet.
لم أحمل حفيدًا بعد.
I still want to live to 180!
ما زلت أريد أن أعيش حتى 180!
I had no choice.
لم يكن لدي خيار.
I was forced into this.
تم إجباري على هذا.
Besides...
بالإضافة إلى ذلك...
His Highness truly cares for me.
صاحب السمو يهتم بي حقًا.
He said he knew all along,
قال إنه كان يعلم طوال الوقت،
and he never exposed me.
ولم يكشفني أبدًا.
Whether he did or didn't expose you doesn't matter!
سواء كشفك أم لا، هذا لا يهم!
Sure, Prince Jin might protect you.
بالتأكيد، الأمير جين قد يحميك.
But His Majesty?
لكن جلالته؟
You think he will let it go?
هل تعتقد أنه سيتغاضى عن ذلك؟
He likes Prince Jin so much...
إنه يحب الأمير جين كثيرًا...
Maybe he'll forgive me too?
ربما سيغفر لي أيضًا؟
Maybe it'll be fine, right?
ربما سيكون الأمر على ما يرام، أليس كذلك؟
Maybe?
ربما؟
Manman, use your head!
مانمان، استخدم عقلك!
You lied to His Majesty!
لقد كذبت على جلالته!
That's treason!
هذا خيانة!
Treason means death!
الخيانة تعني الموت!
Ji Mo...
جي مو...
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
You conspired with a criminal to deceive us!
لقد تآمرت مع مجرم لخداعنا!
Take him away.
خذوه بعيدًا.
Execute him!
أعدموه!
No!
لا!
Father!
أبي!
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Qiao Manman!
تشياو مانمان!
Why did you have to say it?
لماذا كان عليك أن تقولها؟
You got us all killed!
لقد تسببت في قتلنا جميعًا!
Qiao Manman!
تشياو مانمان!
Qiao Manman is an impostor posing as the Xilin Princess,
تشياو مانمان محتالة تتظاهر بأنها أميرة زيلين،
married into Prince Jin's Residence.
وتزوجت في مقر الأمير جين.
Manman, why did you confess?
مانمان، لماذا اعترفت؟
Why did you confess?
لماذا اعترفت؟
She shall be beheaded, as a warning to all.
يجب قطع رأسها كتحذير للجميع.
No!
لا!
We promised to trust each other.
لقد وعدنا بالثقة ببعضنا البعض.
I must speak with him.
يجب أن أتحدث معه.
Manman! Manman!
مانمان! مانمان!
Yes.
نعم.
Take this with you.
خذ هذا معك.
Wait, Dear. What are you doing with that?
انتظري، عزيزتي. ماذا تفعلين بهذا؟
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
I'm just a little nervous.
أنا فقط متوترة قليلاً.
Nervous about what?
متوترة من ماذا؟
It's just an exam.
إنه مجرد امتحان.
I'm right here.
أنا هنا.
You'll do great. Your name will top the board.
ستبلي بلاءً حسنًا. اسمك سيكون في القمة.
Alright.
حسنًا.
Make way!
أفسحوا الطريق!
Excuse me.
اعذرني.
(Xiufeng Academy) Sorry, let us through.
(أكاديمية شيوفنغ) عذرًا، اسمحوا لنا بالمرور.
I'll make us proud.
سأجعلنا فخورين.
Coming through!
أنا قادم!
Dear, we're finally here!
عزيزي، لقد وصلنا أخيرًا!
Here, let me wipe your sweat.
هنا، دعني أمسح عرقك.
You're not sweating.
أنت لا تتعرق.
Then, drink some water.
إذن، اشرب بعض الماء.
I'm not thirsty, Fang.
لست عطشانًا، فانغ.
Have a bite.
تناول قضمة.
I'm not hungry.
لست جائعًا.
You need energy for the exam.
أنت بحاجة إلى طاقة للامتحان.
It's fine. I'm really not hungry.
لا بأس. أنا حقًا لست جائعًا.
You're a lucky man.
أنت رجل محظوظ.
Not everyone
ليس الجميع
is as fortunate.
محظوظًا مثلك.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
My husband is blessed.
زوجي مبارك.
What?
ماذا؟
Yes, you are absolutely right.
نعم، أنت على حق تمامًا.
Dear, keep your voice down.
عزيزي، اخفض صوتك.
Why should I?
لماذا أفعل ذلك؟
What's there to be afraid of?
ما الذي نخشاه؟
You're the best.
أنت الأفضل.
Give it your best today.
بذل أقصى ما لديك اليوم.
You're the best!
أنت الأفضل!
You really are the best!
أنت حقًا الأفضل!
I'll do my best.
سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
You're the best, my dear!
أنت الأفضل، عزيزي!
Absolutely the best.
بالتأكيد الأفضل.
The very best.
الأفضل على الإطلاق.
You're peerless.
أنت لا مثيل لك.
You're the best,
أنت الأفضل،
and you're going to top the exam!
وستتفوق في الامتحان!
Candidate Ji Mo!
المرشح جي مو!
It's your turn, Dear.
حان دورك، عزيزي.
Good luck!
حظًا سعيدًا!
Don't be nervous.
لا تتوتر.
You can do it.
يمكنك فعلها.
I believe in you.
أنا أؤمن بك.
Alright, I'll do my very best.
حسنًا، سأبذل قصارى جهدي.
Candidate Ji Mo!
المرشح جي مو!
Everything's ready.
كل شيء جاهز.
Yes.
نعم.
He's going in.
إنه يدخل.
Go on.
استمر.
Are you Ji Mo?
هل أنت جي مو؟
Yes, sir.
نعم، سيدي.
Good.
جيد.
Right this way.
من هنا.
(Ji Mo)
(جي مو)
The exam begins.
بدأ الاختبار.
"What is there to fear in being a woman..."
"ما الذي تخشاه في كونك امرأة..."
(If she finds a good man?) Fear...
(إذا وجدت رجلاً صالحاً؟) الخوف...
(Build a family...)
(بناء عائلة...)
(Then, pursue one's aspirations.)
(ثم، السعي وراء الطموحات.)
(Find the right one and build a home. Then, pursue your aspirations.)
(ابحث عن الشخص المناسب وابنِ منزلاً. ثم، اسعَ وراء طموحاتك.)
Good luck.
حظاً سعيداً.
(Find the right one and build a home. Then, pursue your aspirations.)
(ابحث عن الشخص المناسب وابنِ منزلاً. ثم، اسعَ وراء طموحاتك.)
(Benevolent and Kind)
(طيب القلب ولطيف)
Where did you run off to?
إلى أين هربت؟
You were gone all day.
كنت غائباً طوال اليوم.
Yuetao said you even skipped breakfast.
قال يوتاو إنك حتى تخطيت الإفطار.
I couldn't eat.
لم أستطع الأكل.
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
You may have accepted me,
ربما تكون قد قبلتني،
but that doesn't mean your father accepts me as well.
لكن هذا لا يعني أن والدك يقبلني أيضاً.
What if he finds out I'm not the real princess?
ماذا لو اكتشف أنني لست الأميرة الحقيقية؟
What then?
ماذا بعد ذلك؟
Come.
تعال.
Come here.
تعال إلى هنا.
Sit down.
اجلس.
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
(Saibei Desert, Mount Tianbao, Northlands, Luzhao Kingdom)
(صحراء سايباي، جبل تيانباو، الشمال، مملكة لوزهاو)
What are all these places?
ما هي كل هذه الأماكن؟
Before I met you,
قبل أن ألتقي بك،
I had already planned to leave these struggles behind
كنت قد خططت بالفعل لترك هذه الصراعات ورائي
to live a quiet life in the countryside.
للعيش حياة هادئة في الريف.
But now that I've met you,
ولكن الآن بعد أن التقيت بك،
we can leave together.
يمكننا المغادرة معًا.
Leave the capital.
مغادرة العاصمة.
Follow the Northlands to the desert and watch the sunrise.
اتبع الشمال إلى الصحراء وشاهد شروق الشمس.
Then, cross the western mountains and reach Mirror Lake.
ثم، اعبر الجبال الغربية ووصل إلى بحيرة المرآة.
And finally, take a boat
وأخيرًا، استقل قاربًا
(Eastern Lake) along the eastern shore.
(بحيرة الشرق) على طول الشاطئ الشرقي.
What do you think?
ما رأيك؟
Mountains or lakes,
جبال أو بحيرات،
wherever you go,
أينما تذهب،
I'll follow.
سأتبعك.
But your father definitely won't be pleased.
ولكن والدك بالتأكيد لن يكون سعيدًا.
He thinks so highly of you.
إنه يفكر فيك كثيرًا.
Can you convince him?
هل يمكنك إقناعه؟
Do you truly not want to be the next ruler?
هل حقًا لا تريد أن تكون الحاكم القادم؟
Compared to me,
مقارنة بي،
Yunnuo may be a bit hot-tempered,
يونو قد يكون سريع الغضب قليلاً،
but his talent and tactics
لكن موهبته وتكتيكاته
are on par with mine.
على قدم المساواة معي.
If he takes over the throne,
إذا تولى العرش،
I'll have no worries.
لن يكون لدي أي قلق.
Even when praising others,
حتى عند مدح الآخرين،
you praise yourself first.
أنت تمدح نفسك أولاً.
Manman...
مانمان...
Would you be willing to leave with me?
هل ستكونين مستعدة للمغادرة معي؟
Once we leave the palace,
بمجرد أن نغادر القصر،
life may not be as comfortable anymore.
قد لا تكون الحياة مريحة كما كانت.
Don't forget.
لا تنسى.
I was never a real princess.
لم أكن أبدًا أميرة حقيقية.
Wherever you go,
أينما تذهب،
I'll follow.
سأتبعك.
We'll be inseparable.
سنكون لا ينفصلان.
Alright, I'm starving.
حسنًا، أنا جائع.
Let's go grab a bite.
لنذهب لتناول شيء.
Alright, let's go.
حسنًا، لنذهب.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Your Highness, it's time for your medicine.
سموك، حان وقت تناول دوائك.
Please, Your Highness. Your health comes first.
من فضلك، سموك. صحتك تأتي أولاً.
Princess Consort Jin...
الأميرة القرينة جين...
Enough.
يكفي.
Where is Hu Ersa now?
أين هو إرسا الآن؟
(Xiufeng Academy)
(أكاديمية شيوفنغ)
I wonder how he did on the exam.
أتساءل كيف أدى في الامتحان.
Yeah, it's driving me crazy!
نعم، هذا يدفعني للجنون!
It's been way too long.
لقد مر وقت طويل جدًا.
Miss,
آنسة،
how are you not nervous at all?
كيف لا تشعرين بالتوتر على الإطلاق؟
My husband's a walking library.
زوجي مكتبة متنقلة.
Why should I worry?
لماذا يجب أن أقلق؟
I'm just waiting to become the top scholar's wife.
أنا فقط أنتظر لأصبح زوجة الطالب الأول.
Is that so...
هل هذا صحيح...
Dear!
عزيزي!
You're out!
لقد خرجت!
As expected from you.
كما هو متوقع منك.
You even handed it in early!
حتى أنك سلمته مبكرًا!
Let's talk at home.
لنتحدث في المنزل.
What's wrong?
ما الخطأ؟
Did it not go well?
ألم تسر الأمور على ما يرام؟
It's alright if it didn't go well.
لا بأس إذا لم تسر الأمور على ما يرام.
There's always a next time.
هناك دائمًا فرصة أخرى.
You must be hungry.
لا بد أنك جائع.
We can...
يمكننا...
Can I just have a moment alone?
هل يمكنني الحصول على لحظة وحدي؟
Dear?
عزيزي؟
(Everything Guild)
(نقابة كل شيء)
When he walked in,
عندما دخل،
he just sat there in silence?
هل جلس هناك في صمت؟
He's always like that.
هو دائماً هكذا.
Look at him.
انظر إليه.
Nothing like how his father used to be.
لا شيء مثل ما كان عليه والده.
But I know my son.
لكنني أعرف ابني.
He's a thinker.
إنه مفكر.
Unlike me,
على عكسي،
I am carefree.
أنا غير مكترث.
No, Dad...
لا، أبي...
That's not what I meant at all.
هذا ليس ما قصدته على الإطلاق.
Son!
يا بني!
Come down, quick!
انزل بسرعة!
- Dear, what are you doing? - Don't do anything rash!
- عزيزي، ماذا تفعل؟ - لا تفعل أي شيء طائش!
I was just joking!
كنت أمزح فقط!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Come down!
انزل!
It's just an exam!
إنه مجرد امتحان!
Why are you taking it so hard?
لماذا تأخذه بهذه الصعوبة؟
What's wrong with you?
ما خطبك؟
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
No, Father! Fang!
لا، أبي! فانغ!
I was tying my hair up for motivation!
كنت أربط شعري لأحفز نفسي!
Tying your hair up?
تربط شعرك؟
My son may be thoughtful,
قد يكون ابني مفكراً،
but he wouldn't hang himself!
لكنه لن يشنق نفسه!
Even tying my hair up won't help.
حتى ربط شعري لن يساعد.
Even stabbing my leg won't help.
حتى طعن ساقي لن يساعد.
I'm really just hopeless.
أنا حقاً بلا أمل.
Son,
يا بني،
it's just one exam.
إنه مجرد امتحان واحد.
Is this necessary?
هل هذا ضروري؟
If you didn't do well,
إذا لم تنجح،
then try again next time.
فحاول مرة أخرى في المرة القادمة.
And if not that time,
وإذا لم تنجح في تلك المرة،
then the time after that. Right?
ففي المرة التي تليها. أليس كذلك؟
Here, have some water.
هنا، خذ بعض الماء.
Dad...
أبي...
Look at me. I'm an adult.
انظر إلي. أنا بالغ.
I've achieved nothing.
لم أحقق شيئاً.
Plus...
بالإضافة إلى ذلك...
I'm still living off you.
ما زلت أعيش على حسابك.
I'm your father!
أنا والدك!
I feed you. So what?
أنا أطعمك. فماذا في ذلك؟
But you can't support me forever, Dad!
لكنك لا تستطيع أن تدعمني إلى الأبد، أبي!
I...
أنا...
Even if it's forever, I can do it.
حتى لو كان إلى الأبد، أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.
♪The clouds stretch endlessly across the sky♪
♪تمتد السحب بلا نهاية عبر السماء♪
♪Looking down at eyes that gaze into the distance♪
♪أنظر إلى عيون تحدق في البعيد♪
♪Time keeps moving on♪
♪الزمن يستمر في التقدم♪
♪Whose footprints are left behind?♪
♪من الذي ترك آثاره خلفه؟♪
♪It's more than just the courage to yearn♪
♪إنه أكثر من مجرد الشجاعة للشوق♪
♪It's destined that we cannot be close♪
♪مقدر لنا ألا نكون قريبين♪
♪Loving you is a secret♪
♪حبك سرٌّ♪
♪Afraid of disturbing you and then you'd distance yourself♪
♪أخشى أن أزعجك فتتباعد عني♪
♪Endlessly♪
♪بلا نهاية♪
♪How I wish I could dive into the sea♪
♪كم أتمنى أن أغوص في البحر♪
♪And gently rest♪
♪وأستريح بلطف♪
♪It's to soothe the reason for your heart's pain♪
♪لتهدئة سبب ألم قلبك♪
♪If everything could overcome all barriers and fall in love♪
♪إذا كان كل شيء يمكنه تجاوز كل الحواجز والوقوع في الحب♪
♪Even the cloud and sea could be together♪
♪حتى السحابة والبحر يمكن أن يكونا معًا♪
♪Forget how far from shore and how dangerous it is♪
♪انسَ مدى البعد عن الشاطئ ومدى خطورته♪
♪We can't see♪
♪لا نستطيع الرؤية♪
♪If distance can't tear us apart and it's not hard to endure♪
♪إذا كانت المسافة لا يمكنها أن تفرقنا وليس من الصعب تحملها♪
♪Our tears will stay together♪
♪دموعنا ستبقى معًا♪
♪Don’t forget the love♪
♪لا تنسَ الحب♪
♪They could never have♪
♪الذي لم يستطيعوا الحصول عليه أبدًا♪